Eric Son

www.ymericson.com| yson@uchicago.edu | 703-501-8614

SUMMARY

Developer with 5 years of experience in data analysis, data-intensive applications, automation tools, and machine learning deployments. Background in software engineering and big data architecture including AWS, Hadoop, Spark, and Hive. Graduate student studying CS and public policy in the University of Chicago.

EXPERIENCE

National Institutes of Health

Bethesda, MD

Civic Digital Fellow – Data Science

June 2020 - Dec. 2020

- Built web applications for real time display of the Central Utility Plant's \$70M annual energy consumption data
- Worked closely with lead engineers to design of ETL processes and database structure
- Integrated an input form to enter and search 8 years of utility records, and a visualization dashboard that summarizes on-site energy usage and cost avoidance data

Center for Municipal Finance

Chicago, IL

Research Assistant

Jan. 2020 – June 2020

- Built a reproducible data pipeline that outputted reports for tax regressivity in America, identifying counties that had a regressive tax assessment system that makes low-income property owners pay a higher share of property tax
- Generated an overview of the assessments completed by the Cook County Assessor's Office using eight years of FOIArequested data

EAB Global Richmond, VA

Strategic Targeting Analyst

Oct. 2016 - July 2019

- Key achievement: reduced operation execution time for 250+ undergraduate clients by 90% through an initiative to develop Python web-application automation tools
- Identified contact opportunities for 80+ clients by developing a reporting tool that analyzed national student datasets
- Applied predictive analytics model across enrollment pipeline for clients to meet incoming class goals, with a focus on direct marketing campaign to prospective students and recent high-school graduates

Colonial Williamsburg Bruton Heights Education Center

Williamsburg, VA

Program Associate (Education, Research and Historical Interpretation)

Apr. 2015 - June 2016

- Led the data migration of 200+ education resources to a new data warehouse for online access
- Researched and produced teacher development content and programming for distance learning

PROJECTS

<u>Chicago Streets Stats</u> – Big Data AWS web app that displays historical/current street congestion, crashes, and traffic violations <u>City of Chicago Salaries</u> – Shiny web app that shows interactive tree map and searchable table of Chicago govt. employees <u>Housing Affordability Prediction</u> – predict housing affordability in Chicago neighborhoods using price-to-income ratio <u>U.S. Energy Consumption</u> – Django web app that displays U.S. state energy consumption trends since 1950

EDUCATION

University of Chicago

Chicago, IL

Master of Science in Computational Analysis and Public Policy

Expected June 2021

College of William and Mary

Williamsburg, VA May 2015

Bachelor of Arts in Economics and Film/Media Studies

SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, Java, Stata, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Framework: Django, Bottle, Flask

Visualization: Tableau, ArcGIS, QlikView, Power BI

Big Data: Hadoop, Hive, Spark, HBase, Kafka **Data Database**: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite **Other**: Adobe Creative Suite, Apple Final Cut Pro